Jane Dyer Papers
© 2005 University of Connecticut
Jane Dyer Papers.
undated, 1986-2000.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Dyer, Jane.
6 linear feet.
The collection contains materials pertaining to the development and creation of 14 books.
MSS19910043
Biography
Published Works:
Animal Crackers, 1996. CLC D380
Animal Crackers: bedtime, 1998. CLC A750
Animal Crackers: nursery rhymes, 1998. CLC A871
Blue Moon Soup by Goss, Gary, 1999. CLC C1833
Girl in the Golden Bower by Yolen, Jane, 1994. CLC C1975
If Anything Ever Goes Wrong at the Zoo by Hendrick, Mary Jean, 1993. CLC C906
My Father by Collins, Judy, 1989. CLC C1800
The Patchwork Lady by Whittington, Mary K., 1991. CLC C429
Talking Like the Rain by Kennedy, X.J. and Dorothy, 1992. CLC D375
Time for Bed by Fox, Mem, 1993. CLC D378
When Mama Comes Home Tonight by Spinelli, Eileen, 1998. CLC D379
Scope and Content
The collection contains original art, research material, photographs, sketches, dummies, manuscripts, galleys, proofs, correspondence, publicity material, and reviews from 1986-2000 (bulk, 1989-1997). There are several oversized posterboards, that show the process of how the illustrator progressed from research material to sketches to the finished illustration, that were used at book fairs, schools, and presentations.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of children's literature and associated artwork. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Bibliography
About the Author:
producer,Billie M. Levy; director, Paul Giguere. Children's books, their creators and collectors. Guest, Jane Dyer [videorecording], [West Hartford, Conn.]: WHC-TV, c1994. Dodd Video Cassette PN1009.A1 C458
compiled and edited by Pat Cummings. Talking With Artists. Volume 3 /, New York: Clarion Books, 1999.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Subjects:
Document Types:
Artwork.; Dummies.; Correspondence.; Publications.; Photographs.; Illustrations.; Manuscripts.; Galley proofs.; Books.
Occupations:
Illustrator.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The Collection has been donated by Jane Dyer in multiple installments beginning in 1993.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Children's Books, undated, 1986-2000
  - Animal Crackers 1996
    - Notes, undated (Box 4:, Folder 127)
    - Thumbnail Sketches (cover), undated (Box 4:, Folder 128)
    - Jacket Design Sketches, undated (Box 4:, Folder 129)
    - Type Samples, undated (Box 4:, Folder 130)
    - Cover Type Samples and Acetate Overlay, undated (Box 4:, Folder 131)
    - Correspondence, 1993-1995 (Box 4:, Folder 132)
    - Proof (incomplete), ca. 1996 (Box 7:, Folder 198)
    - Original Sketch and Mock-up, undated (Box 7:, Folder 199)
    - Index (mock-up), undated (Box 7:, Folder 200)
    - Author's Galleys, 1994 February (Box 7:, Folder 201)
    - Type Samples, undated (Box 7:, Folder 202)
    - Jacket Design Sketches, undated (Box 7:, Folder 203)
    - Cover Proofs (photocopy, marked up), 1995 (Box 7:, Folder 204)
    - Jacket Proof, undated (Box 7:, Folder 205)
    - Illustrator's Marked-up Proof (cover), undated (Box 7:, Folder 206)
    - Preliminary Sketches (tracing paper), undated (Box 9:, Folder 260)
  - Baby Bear's Bedtime Book 1990
    - Sketches, Mock-ups, and Research Material (photocopies), undated (Box 2:, Folder 42)
    - Correspondence, 1989 (Box 2:, Folder 43)
    - Galley (photocopy), 1989 February (Box 9:, Folder 249)
    - Specimen First Proof, undated (Box 9:, Folder 250)
    - Sketches, undated (Box 9:, Folder 251)
  - Child of Faerie, Child of Earth 1997
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 5:, Folder 133)
    - Revised Manuscript, 1994 February (Box 5:, Folder 134)
    - Notes, undated (Box 5:, Folder 135)
    - Research Photographs, 1989 (Box 5:, Folder 136)
    - Research Material, undated (Box 9:, Folder 262)
    - Thumbnail Sketches and Preliminary Sketches, undated (Box 9:, Folder 263)
    - Preliminary Sketches and Research Material
      - “Wren”, undated (Box 5:, Folder 137)
      - “He's Taken Her by Her Dirt Soiled Hand and Led Her to His Hall... (See underground)”, undated (Box 5:, Folder 138)
      - “In the Fairy Hall”, undated (Box 5:, Folder 139)
      - “Oh, Stay with Me Dear Human Child Become a Child of the Night”, undated (Box 5:, Folder 140)
      - “Oh Stay with Me Dear Human Child Become a Child of the Night”, undated (Box 7:, Folder 207)
      - “I Cannot On Your Food Be Fed and Still My Needs Fulfill”, undated (Box 5:, Folder 141)
      - “She Led Him Down the Farmhouse Road...”, undated (Box 5:, Folder 142)
      - “She Led Him Down the Farmhouse Road...”, undated (Box 7:, Folder 209)
      - “He's Looked Around the Human World...”, undated (Box 5:, Folder 143)
      - “Landscapes (earth)”, undated (Box 5:, Folder 144)
      - “He Thought about the Fairy Halls”, undated (Box 5:, Folder 145)
      - “Oh, Wait, Oh Wait”, undated (Box 5:, Folder 146)
      - “Child of Faerie Title Page”, undated (Box 5:, Folder 147)
      - “And Where Do You Go, Oh Child of Earth”, undated (Box 7:, Folder 208)
      - “Farm”, undated (Box 7:, Folder 210)
      - “They Stroked the Cat”, undated (Box 7:, Folder 211)
      - “Oh, Stay with Me Dear Faerie Child”, undated (Box 7:, Folder 212)
      - “At Last She Found a Fresh Hen's Egg”, undated (Box 7:, Folder 213)
      - “I Give You This That Comes from That”, undated (Box 7:, Folder 214)
      - “The Gifts Exchanged, They Each Went Back”, undated (Box 7:, Folder 215)
    - Preliminary Sketches and Research Material, undated (Box 7:, Folder 216)
    - Preliminary Mock-up, ca. 1996 (Box 5:, Folder 148)
    - Mock-ups and Sketches (photocopies), undated (Box 5:, Folder 149)
    - Mock-up, undated (Box 5:, Folder 150)
    - Mock-up, undated (Box 5:, Folder 151)
    - Type Sample, undated (Box 5:, Folder 152)
    - Proof (photocopy), undated (Box 5:, Folder 153)
    - Correspondence, 1995, 1997 (Box 5:, Folder 154)
    - Galley (marked up), 1995 August (Box 7:, Folder 217)
    - Illustrator's Galleys, 1995 August (Box 7:, Folder 218)
    - Revised Galley (page 3), 1995 September (Box 7:, Folder 219)
    - First Proof Jacket, undated (Box 7:, Folder 220)
    - Fourth Proof Illustrator, ca. 1997 (Box 7:, Folder 221)
    - Proof (photocopy), undated (Box 9:, Folder 261)
  - Girl in the Golden Bower 1994
    - Manuscript, 1992 (Box 3:, Folder 89)
    - Research Material, undated (Box 3:, Folder 90)
    - Research Material, undated (Box 3:, Folder 91)
    - Research Photographs, undated (Box 3:, Folder 92)
    - Notes, undated (Box 3:, Folder 93)
    - Thumbnail Sketches, undated (Box 3:, Folder 94)
    - Preliminary Sketches and Research Material, undated (Box 3:, Folder 95)
      - “Frail Young Woman”, undated (Box 3:, Folder 96)
    - Preliminary Sketches and Research Material, undated (Box 3:, Folder 97)
    - Preliminary Sketches and Research Material, undated (Box 3:, Folder 98)
    - Preliminary Sketches and Research Material, undated (Box 3:, Folder 99)
      - “Woodsman Dying, Moonlight and Shadow Outside Window”, undated (Box 3:, Folder 100)
      - “Curry Combing Animal's Hair”, undated (Box 3:, Folder 101)
    - Preliminary Sketches and Research Material, undated (Box 3:, Folder 102)
      - “Sorceress”, undated (Box 3:, Folder 103)
    - Preliminary Sketches and Research Material, undated (Box 3:, Folder 104)
    - Preliminary Sketches and Research Material, undated (Box 3:, Folder 105)
    - Preliminary Sketches and Research Material, undated (Box 3:, Folder 106)
    - Preliminary Sketches and Research Material, undated (Box 3:, Folder 107)
      - “Then I Am Your Daughter's Daughter”, undated (Box 3:, Folder 108)
    - Preliminary Sketches and Research Material, undated (Box 3:, Folder 109)
    - Type Samples, undated (Box 3:, Folder 110)
    - Proof (one page only), undated (Box 3:, Folder 111)
    - Correspondence, 1990-1994 (Box 3:, Folder 112)
    - Poster (photocopy), 1994 (Box 9:, Folder 265)
    - Posterboards Documenting the Creation Process, undated (Box 10:, Folder 271)
    - Preliminary Sketches, undated (Box 7:, Folder 193)
    - Galley, 1992 October (Box 7:, Folder 194)
  - If Anything Ever Goes Wrong at the Zoo 1993
    - Notes, undated (Box 2:, Folder 59)
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 2:, Folder 60)
    - Research Photographs, undated (Box 2:, Folder 61)
    - Research Material, undated (Box 2:, Folder 62)
    - Research Material, undated (Box 2:, Folder 63)
    - Research Material, undated (Box 2:, Folder 64)
    - Research Material, undated (Box 6:, Folder 181)
    - Sketches, undated (Box 2:, Folder 65)
    - Thumbnail Sketches, undated (Box 6:, Folder 182)
    - Title Page Ideas, Sketches, and Mock-ups, undated (Box 2:, Folder 66)
    - Galley (photocopy), 1991 (Box 2:, Folder 67)
    - Type Samples, 1991 (Box 2:, Folder 68)
    - Title Acetate Overlays, undated (Box 2:, Folder 69)
    - First Proof (incomplete), ca. 1993 (Box 2:, Folder 70)
    - First Proof (partial text), ca. 1993 (Box 2:, Folder 71)
    - Proof, ca. 1993 (Box 2:, Folder 72)
    - Correspondence, 1991-1994 (Box 2:, Folder 73)
    - Reviews, 1993 (Box 2:, Folder 74)
    - Blurbs from Rights Guide, 1993 (Box 2:, Folder 75)
  - My Father 1989
    - “Ad in Boston Globe that Reinforced Idea” (photocopy), Nov. 1987 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
    - Lyrics and Music, undated (Box 1:, Folder 6)
    - Thumbnails for Mss Layout, undated (Box 1:, Folder 7)
    - Notes, undated (Box 1:, Folder 8)
    - Research Photographs (Box 1:, Folder 9)
    - “Photographs (for reference)”, undated
    - Research Material, undated (Box 1:, Folder 10)
    - Ribbon Used for Illustration, undated (Box 1:, Folder 273)
    - Preliminary Sketches and Research Material
      - “Always Promised Us”, undated (Box 1:, Folder 11)
      - “Boating on the Seine”, undated (Box 1:, Folder 12)
      - “And I Would Learn to Dance”, undated (Box 1:, Folder 13)
      - “We Lived in Ohio Then”, undated (Box 1:, Folder 14)
      - “We Lived in Ohio Then”, undated (Box 1:, Folder 15)
      - “He Worked in the Mines”, undated (Box 1:, Folder 16)
      - “On His Streams”, undated (Box 1:, Folder 17)
      - “All My Sisters Soon Were Gone”, undated (Box 1:, Folder 18)
      - “All My Sisters Soon Were Gone”, undated (Box 1:, Folder 19)
      - “Marrying”, undated (Box 1:, Folder 20)
      - “Stayed Behind”, undated (Box 1:, Folder 21)
      - “Stayed Behind”, undated (Box 1:, Folder 22)
      - “The Colors of”, undated (Box 1:, Folder 23)
      - “And I Live in Paris Now”, undated (Box 1:, Folder 24)
      - “Hearing the Ways”, undated (Box 1:, Folder 25)
      - “I Sail Memories”, undated (Box 1:, Folder 26)
      - “Sunset”, undated (Box 1:, Folder 27)
      - “Title”, undated (Box 1:, Folder 28)
      - “Dedication”, undated (Box 1:, Folder 29)
      - “Cover”, undated (Box 1:, Folder 30)
      - “Foil Stamp”, undated (Box 1:, Folder 31)
    - “My Father (Sketches Not Used)”, undated (Box 1:, Folder 32)
    - Preliminary Mock-up, undated (Box 1:, Folder 33)
    - Mock-up, undated (Box 1:, Folder 34)
    - “Mock-up of Case”, undated (Box 1:, Folder 35)
    - Proof, ca. 1989 (Box 1:, Folder 36)
    - Proofs “We Lived In Ohio Then”, ca. 1989 (Box 1:, Folder 37)
    - Reviews and Interviews, undated, 1989, 1990 (Box 1:, Folder 38)
    - “Letter to the Editor from Bookseller (report)” [photocopy], 1989 (Box 1:, Folder 39)
    - “Signings” (photographs), 1989 November (Box 1:, Folder 40)
    - Correspondence, 1988-1990 (Box 1:, Folder 41)
    - Uncut Proofs, ca. 1989 (Box 9:, Folder 270)
    - Posterboards Documenting the Creation Process, undated (Box 10:, Folder 272)
    - First Proof Illustrator (jacket), ca. 1989 (Box 9:, Folder 255)
    - Research Material, undated (Box 6:, Folder 168)
    - Preliminary Sketches (photocopies) “Always Promised Us”, undated (Box 6:, Folder 169)
    - Second Proof Illustrator (marked up), ca. 1989 (Box 6:, Folder 170)
    - Proof, Illustrator's Copy (marked up), ca. 1989 (Box 6:, Folder 171)
    - Second Proof Illustrator (with duplicates), ca. 1989 (Box 6:, Folder 172)
    - Second Proof Illustrator (with duplicates), ca. 1989 (Box 6:, Folder 173)
    - Preliminary Sketch “Cover”, undated (Box 6:, Folder 174)
    - “Signings”, ca. 1989 (Box 6:, Folder 175)
  - Oh My Baby, Little One 2000
    - Research Material, undated (Box 5:, Folder 158)
    - Research Photographs, undated (Box 5:, Folder 159)
    - Manuscript and Type Samples, undated (Box 5:, Folder 160)
    - Sketches and Mock-ups (photocopies), undated (Box 5:, Folder 161)
    - Correspondence, 1999 (Box 5:, Folder 162)
    - Research Material, undated (Box 8:, Folder 239)
    - Sketches and Mock-ups (photocopies), undated (Box 8:, Folder 240)
    - Sketches and Mock-ups, undated (Box 8:, Folder 241)
    - Sketches and Thumbnail Sketches (photocopies), undated (Box 10:, Folder 266)
  - Peekaboo Farm 2000
    - Notes, undated (Box 5:, Folder 163)
    - Type Sample, undated (Box 5:, Folder 164)
    - Cover Revisions, undated (Box 5:, Folder 165)
    - Correspondence, 1997, 1998 (Box 5:, Folder 166)
    - Research Material (color photograph), undated (Box 8:, Folder 242)
    - Research Material, undated (Box 8:, Folder 243)
    - Mock-ups, undated (Box 8:, Folder 244)
    - Galleys, 1997 October (Box 8:, Folder 245)
    - Galley- Back Cover Blurb, 1998 May (Box 8:, Folder 246)
    - Cover Sketches, undated (Box 8:, Folder 247)
    - Cover Proof, 1998 May (Box 8:, Folder 248)
    - Original Art- Cover “The Big Red Barn”, undated (Box 10:, Folder 267)
    - Sketches, undated (Box 10:, Folder 268)
  - Picnic with Piggins 1988
    - Sketches (photocopies), undated (Box 1:, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1988 March (Box 1:, Folder 4)
    - Original Sketches and Mock-up Sketches, undated (Box 10:, Folder 269)
    - Cover Type Sample, ca. 1988 (Box 6:, Folder 167)
  - Piggins 1987
    - Correspondence, 1986, 1988 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
    - Publicity Packet, 1987 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
    - Original Sketch Mock-ups and Sketches, undated (Box 9:, Folder 252)
    - Uncut Proof, 1987 (Box 9:, Folder 253)
    - Publicity Packet Poster, 1987 (Box 9:, Folder 254)
  - Talking Like the Rain 1992
    - Notes, undated (Box 2:, Folder 44)
    - Research Photographs, undated (Box 2:, Folder 45)
    - “Early Thumbnails: December '89”, 1989 December (Box 2:, Folder 46)
    - Thumbnail Sketches, undated (Box 2:, Folder 47)
    - Research Material, undated (Box 2:, Folder 48)
    - Research Material, undated (Box 6:, Folder 176)
      - “There Was an Old Man W/ a Beard, undated (Box 2:, Folder 49)
      - “Love Is a Green Girl; My Daughter, Brooke; Carl Larson's Old; Man, with My Father's Face”, undated (Box 2:, Folder 50)
    - Preliminary Sketches, undated (Box 2:, Folder 51)
    - Mock-up, undated (Box 2:, Folder 52)
    - Dummy (incomplete, photocopy), undated (Box 2:, Folder 53)
    - Cover and Chapter Heading Type, undated (Box 2:, Folder 54)
    - Transparency, undated (Box 2:, Folder 55)
    - Correspondence, 1989-1993 (Box 2:, Folder 56)
    - Reviews and Announcements, 1992 (Box 2:, Folder 57)
    - Certificate, 1992 (Box 2:, Folder 58)
    - Galley (incomplete), 1990 February (Box 6:, Folder 177)
    - Master Proof- Index and Copyright Ack., 1990 September (Box 6:, Folder 178)
    - Preliminary Sketches, undated (Box 6:, Folder 179)
    - Typeset Overlay, undated (Box 6:, Folder 180)
    - Jacket Proof, undated (Box 9:, Folder 258)
    - Original Art- “black and white illustration given to NCLC to use on book fair poster, 1992” (Box 9:, Folder 259)
  - Three Bears Holiday Rhyme Book 1995
    - Research Material, undated (Box 4:, Folder 113)
    - Sketches and Mock-up Sketches (photocopies), undated (Box 4:, Folder 114)
    - Galley (photocopy), 1993 (Box 4:, Folder 115)
    - Research Material, undated (Box 7:, Folder 195)
    - Galley (photocopy), 1993 June - July (Box 7:, Folder 196)
    - Illustration (photocopy), undated (Box 7:, Folder 197)
    - Notes, undated (Box 9:, Folder 256)
    - Index Manuscript (marked up), undated (Box 4:, Folder 117)
    - Table of Contents Manuscript (marked up), ca. 1995 (Box 4:, Folder 118)
    - First Manuscript (marked up, incomplete), undated (Box 4:, Folder 119)
    - New Manuscript Mock-up (marked up, incomplete), ca. 1995 (Box 4:, Folder 120)
    - Manuscript Mock-up (marked up), undated (Box 4:, Folder 121)
    - Research Material, undated (Box 4:, Folder 122)
    - Preliminary Sketches, undated (Box 4:, Folder 123)
    - Mock-ups, undated (Box 4:, Folder 124)
    - Mock-up (board book), undated (Box 4:, Folder 125)
    - Table of Contents Sample, undated (Box 4:, Folder 126)
  - Time for Bed 1993
    - Notes On and History of, 1993 October (Box 3:, Folder 76)
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 3:, Folder 77)
    - Reference Material, undated (Box 3:, Folder 78)
    - Preliminary Sketches and Mock-ups (photocopies), undated (Box 3:, Folder 79)
    - Editor's Comments, 1992 April (Box 3:, Folder 80)
    - Type Samples, undated, 1992 May (Box 3:, Folder 81)
    - Acetate Overlays and Cut Up Text for Paste Ups, undated (Box 3:, Folder 82)
    - Type, Color Samples, and Acetate Overlays for Title Page, undated (Box 3:, Folder 83)
    - First Proof (small book), ca. 1993 (Box 3:, Folder 84)
    - Correspondence, 1992-1995 (Box 3:, Folder 85)
    - Advertisements, 1993 (Box 3:, Folder 86)
    - Reviews, Bestseller Lists, and ABBY Nominee List, 1993-1995 (Box 3:, Folder 87)
    - Rights Guide, 1992 (Box 3:, Folder 88)
    - Thumbnail Sketches, undated (Box 6:, Folder 183)
    - Australian Contract, 1993 (Box 6:, Folder 184)
    - Review and Bestseller List, 1994 January (Box 6:, Folder 185)
    - First Proof (jacket only), 1993 (Box 6:, Folder 186)
    - Production First Proofs (incomplete), ca. 1993 (Box 6:, Folder 187)
    - Production First Proof (photocopy), undated (Box 6:, Folder 188)
    - Production Second Proof, ca. 1993 (Box 6:, Folder 189)
    - Production Second Proof (photocopy), undated (Box 6:, Folder 190)
    - Publicity Poster, 1994 (Box 6:, Folder 191)
    - Proof (jacket), ca. 1993 (Box 6:, Folder 192)
    - Poster, 1993 (Box 9:, Folder 264)
  - When Mama Comes Home Tonight 1998
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 5:, Folder 155)
    - Research Material Photographs and Negs., undated (Box 5:, Folder 156)
    - Correspondence, 1997 (Box 5:, Folder 157)
    - Notes, undated (Box 8:, Folder 222)
    - Thumbnail Sketches, undated (Box 8:, Folder 223)
    - Preliminary Sketches and Research Material
      - “Hug You Sweet and Tight”, undated (Box 8:, Folder 224)
      - “Dance You Down the Hall”, undated (Box 8:, Folder 225)
      - “Pattycake”, undated (Box 8:, Folder 226)
      - “At Window”, undated (Box 8:, Folder 227)
      - “Blocks”, undated (Box 8:, Folder 228)
      - “Cup of Tea”, undated (Box 8:, Folder 229)
      - “Bath”, undated (Box 8:, Folder 230)
      - “Reading”, undated (Box 8:, Folder 231)
      - “Rocking Chair”, undated (Box 8:, Folder 232)
      - “Lullabies”, undated (Box 8:, Folder 233)
      - “Xeroxes: Photos”, undated (Box 8:, Folder 234)
    - Preliminary Sketches and Research Material, undated (Box 8:, Folder 235)
    - Mock-up (photocopy), undated (Box 8:, Folder 236)
    - Mock-up (photocopy), 1997 (Box 8:, Folder 237)
    - First Proof, ca. 1998 (Box 8:, Folder 238)